## **CHIOMA OTU**

Golf estate 2, Rumudara, Off Tank Junction, Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria.

Phone: 09034454765

Email: Chiomaotu22@gmail.com

## **Profile Summary**

A self-taught web developer with good knowledge and practice of HTML5, CSS3, CSS libraries such as (Tailwind CSS and Bootstrap 4), Responsive Web Design and Vanilla Javascript. Currently learning and working on projects using Javascript frameworks such as JQuery, Vuejs and Reactjs. Other non-related programming experience as a passionate and result-driven teacher with sound knowledge in phonics and elocution. As a Creative writer and researcher with a burning desire to teach and travel. A team player committed to achieving corporate and personal development.

### **Experience**

April 2018 - December 2020.

# Elite Tutors, Port Harcourt, Rivers State - Homeschool teacher/ Phonics instructor

- Reviewed curriculum and devised alternate approaches to presenting lessons to increase pupils' understanding.
- Employed the use of visual aids such as projectors, computer games, board games, puzzles etc. geared towards making learning a fun and fulfilling experience.
- Prepared lesson plans using a strict phonics diet in boosting pupils' reading and spelling abilities.
- Motivated pupils by identifying and amplifying individual strength and turning their weakness into a strong suit.

*August 2014 - February 2015.* 

## Lily Hospitals Limited - Laboratory Intern.

• Mastered the use of Insta-HMS software employed to record and send patients' test results to Doctors on call.

- Learned and performed the basics of blood collection and preservation at the Phlebotomy station of the laboratory.
- Learned and carried out blood tests examination in Haematology station under strict supervision.
- Grasped the mechanics of laboratory equipments and conducted chemical analysis in the Biochemical station under moderate supervision

#### **Education**

February 2012 -February 2016

**University of Port Harcourt, Port Harcourt, Rivers State** - Bachelor of Science

Second class upper division obtained.

#### Certification

January 2018- December 2018

National Youth Service Corps (NYSC).

August 2009- June 2010.

**Indonin Speech Clinic (Phonics, Elocution and Etiquette)** 

#### **Soft Skills**

- Effective Communication
- Team work
- Problem solving
- Creativity
- Organization
- Willingness to learn
- Critical thinking